RG 004:024, Chaplin Probate Court
Connecticut State Library
Chaplin Probate Court records
1850-1950
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Probate (Chaplin District)
6.5 cubic feet
Probate record books, 1850-1950; Probate files, 1850-1926.
RG004_024
1911-003 and 2012-033
Historical Note
Chaplin, Windham County, Town established in May 1822, Parent Towns: Hampton, Mansfield, and Windham
The Chaplin Probate District was constituted June 7, 1850, from the Windham Probate District. The Chaplin Probate District merged with the Eastford Probate District on October 1, 1996 to enlarge the Eastford Probate District. The Chaplin section of the Eastford Probate District merged with the Colchester, Hampton, and Windham Probate Districts on January 5, 2011 to create the Windham - Colchester Probate District, which serves the municipalities of Chaplin, Colchester, Hampton, Lebanon, Scotland, and Windham.
Town of Chaplin, Probate District chronology:
May 1692 - June 6, 1850, Windham District
June 7, 1850 - September 30, 1996, Chaplin District
October 1, 1996 - January 4, 2011, Eastford District
January 5, 2011 - Present, Windham - Colchester District
For Probate Court contact information and hours of operation see,.
Scope and Content
Probate record books, 1850-1929; Wills and Distributions, 1857-1950; Bonds, 1881-1927. Contact the probate court to access record books after Volume E.
Probate files, 1850-1926. Probate files may consist of estates, conservatorships, guardianships, commitments, and insolvencies.
Inventory control book, 1850-1926 (coverage). Also known as the Godard Digest, it is a list of probate files transferred to the Connecticut State Library. It was compiled at the Connecticut State Library under the direction of State Librarian George S. Godard.
Arrangement
Record books are lettered from A to E. There are 2 volumes of Wills and Distributions numbered 1 and 2. There is one Bond volume numbered 1.
Probate files are arranged alphabetically in one series.
Other Finding Aid
Record Books: Index cards for the record books have been scanned. Ask History and Genealogy staff for assistance. Note: CSL does not hold any original record books. See Alternate Form Available section for volumes available on microfilm.
Probate Files: The Probate Estate Papers Index, located in the index corridor adjacent to the History and Genealogy Reading Room, has two parts, a general index covering most of the state, and a Hartford Probate District index covering Hartford and some surrounding towns, 1820-1920. The index cards are arranged alphabetically by individual's last name and first names. The cards have the individual's name, town of residence, probate district, and list of items contained in the estate packet. To request retrieval of an estate packet, copy at least the estate name, file date, and probate district name from the index card. The probate files in Accession 1911-003 are represented in this index.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Probate records -- Connecticut -- Chaplin
Places:
Chaplin (Conn.)
Restrictions on Access
Researchers should first consult use copies when available. See Alternate Form Available Section below.
Probate files from 1921-1926 are RESTRICTED as they may contain confidential documents. Tax returns (succession, transfer and estate tax returns and all attachments) from January 1, 1921 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §12-15.
See the policy.
Alternative Form Available
Record books, volumes A-D, 1850-1915; probate files, 1850-1915; and inventory control book (Godard Digest) were microfilmed by the Genealogical Society of Utah and are available for use in the History and Genealogy reading room or through the.
Provenance
The probate files in accession 1911-003 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on the following dates (with date span of files): October 28, 1911 (1850-1910); April 7, 1927 (to 1926). They were interfiled into one alphabetic sequence.
The record books in accession 2012-033 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on April 19, 2012.
Container List
- Record books, 1850-1950; 3 cubic feet (8 volumes); 2012-033
  - Records, 1850-1892 (Volume A)
  - Records, 1850-1894 (Volume B)
  - Records, 1894-1907 (Volume C)
  - Records, 1907-1919 (Volume D)
  - Records, 1919-1929 (Volume E)
  - Wills and distributions, 1857-1909 (Volume 1)
  - Wills and distributions, 1907-1950 (Volume 2)
  - Bonds, 1881-1927 (Volume 1)
- Probate files, 1850-1926; 3.5 cubic feet; 1911-003
  - Allen - Chaplin (Drawer 1)
  - Chapman - Corey (Drawer 2)
  - Crosby - Day (Drawer 3)
  - Dean - Griggs, C. (Drawer 4)
  - Griggs, D. - Harvey (Drawer 5)
  - Hattin - Knight (Drawer 6)
  - Landon - Martin (Drawer 7)
  - Moran - Reynolds (Drawer 8)
  - Rhoades - Russell (Drawer 9)
  - Sanford - Utley (Drawer 10)
  - Walcott - Z; Miscellaneous (Drawer 11)
- Inventory control book, 1850-1926; T003073
  Index of the two accessions of probate files now merged into accession 1911-003
  Also known as the Godard Digest